Muhammad Touseef

Software Engineer

A passionate software engineer with most experience in Windows Desktop and Web development. "Fluent Video Player" app on Microsoft Store, is one of my main personal projects. I am tech agnostic and love learning new programming languages.

touseefbsb@gmail.com

Islamabad, Pakistan

in linkedin.com/in/touseefbsb

stackoverflow.com/users/5305863/muhammadtouseef +923235978454

touseefbsb.github.io/devportfolio/

github.com/touseefbsb

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer 365 Labs

01/2019 - Present Baton Rouge, Louisiana, USA Enterprise software for law enforcement agencies.

Design->Develop->Maintain

- Fullstack enterprise windows apps.
- UI framework packages for controls and styling.
- .Net 6 Web Apis with Sql Server and SSRS reports as per requirements.
- Code Reviews in CI/CD pipelines.

Remote Uwp Developer Bluebook and Indiestor

03/2017 - 01/2019

Achievements/Tasks

 I have worked remotely in startups like bluebook and indiestor developing uwp apps including tech like smart card integration.

Contact: Alex - Indiestor Limited - alex@indiestor.com

Freelancing

Fiverr and PeoplePerHour

04/2017 - 01/2019

Achievements/Tasks

 I have made multiple uwp apps for clients as a freelancer which polished me as an independent remote developer as well

Microsoft Student Partner

Microsoft

08/2015 - 09/2016

Achievements/Tasks

 I gave seminars on Microsoft tech stack to develop various kinds of apps and also guiding new developers to choose a development path.

EDUCATION

BS-Bioinformatics

Comsats Institute of Information Technology

2013 - 2017

Courses

Biological Algorithms

Computational programming

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Fluent Video Player (2015 - Present)

- A video player app combining efficient playback of all codecs with modern design and fluent features.
- https://apps.microsoft.com/store/detail/9P0JWPR9VN80?hl=en-us&gl=US.

Fluent Sticky Notes (2017 - Present)

 An improved version of sticky notes app with fluent design and picture in picture mode.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Member of Microsoft Virtual Academy Founders Club

https://1drv.ms/b/s!ArmYis0SUpsU5C0YgmEI6ClCkiLM

FYP (Final Year Project)

I created a tool "ChromSACT" (Chromosome Segmentation Annotation and Comparison Toolbox) and it was created as a ASP.Net Core MVC App.

My Published Article

ChromClust: A semi-supervised chromatin clustering toolkit for mining histone modifications interplay - PubMed (nih.gov)

LANGUAGES

English Urdu

Full Professional Proficiency Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

Film-making

Programming

Machine Learning